Herb Staehr Collection ARC.0029
Library and Archives
- Series VI: Concert, Studio, and Television Recordings [RESTRICTED], circa 1960s-2000s
  - Subseries 2: DVD-Video, circa 1960s-2000s
    - Various
      - Rock and Roll: The Greatest Years, undated (Box 14, Object 1-7)
      - Rock and Roll Years, undated (Box 14, Object 8)
      - Rock Family Trees: The British R&B Boom, undated (Box 14, Object 9)
      - Rock television clips with Beatles at the Hollywood Bowl, James Brown, Rolling Stones, Doors, Dave Clark Five, Grateful Dead, undated (Box 14, Object 10)
      - Rock-Pop In Concert, Best of with Status Quo, Foreigner, Joe Cocker, Rod Stewart, Chicago, ZZ Top, Dire Straits, U2, Eurhythmics, UB40, undated (Box 14, Object 11)
      - Rockpalast, Best of with Peter Ruechel, Pete Townshend, Tom Waits, Little Steven, Lynyrd Skynyrd, undated (Box 14, Object 12)
      - Roy Orbison Tribute Concert to Benefit the Homeless, 1990 May (Box 14, Object 13)
      - Scandinavian television compilation with Animals, Jethro Tull, Who, Jeff Beck, Hollies, undated (Box 14, Object 14)
      - Shindig!
        - British Invasion, Volume 1-2, undated (Box 14, Object 15)
        - Shindig! Goes to London, undated (Box 14, Object 16)
        - Sixties Superstars, undated (Box 14, Object 17)
        - Volume 1-2, undated (Box 14, Object 18)
      - PBS Sixties Rock Experience, 2005 March (Box 14, Object 19-20)
      - Smothers Brothers Comedy Hour
        - Compilation, undated (Box 14, Object 21-24)
        - E! Channel rebroadcasts, undated (Box 14, Object 25-26)
      - Sounds of the Seventies, undated (Box 14, Object 27)
      - Sounds of the Sixties (Box 14, Object 28-31)
      - Spector Sound, undated (Box 14, Object 32)
      - Super Night of Rock 'n' Roll, 1984 (Box 14, Object 33)
      - Texas Pop Festival: Got No Shoes, Got No Blues, 1969 August 30-1969 September 1 (Box 14, Object 34)
      - Time-Life History of Rock and Roll
        - Britain Invades, America Fights Back, undated (Box 14, Object 35)
        - Guitar Heroes, undated (Box 14, Object 36)
        - My Generation, undated (Box 14, Object 37)
        - Plugging In, undated (Box 14, Object 38)
        - Rock and Roll Explodes, undated (Box 14, Object 39)
        - Seventies: Have a Nice Decade, undated (Box 14, Object 40)
      - Top of the Pops: compilation, 1971-1979 (Box 14, Object 41)
      - When the Music's Over, undated (Box 14, Object 42-43)
      - Woodstock outtakes #1 with Creedence Clearwater Revival, Crosby, Stills, Nash, and Young, Janis Joplin, Jefferson Airplane, Band, 1969 (Box 14, Object 45)
      - X-Large Guitar Heroes, 1989 (Box 13, Object 101)
    - Vaughan, Stevie Ray
      - Munich, Germany; Austin Music Awards with Fabulous Thunderbirds; Maui, Hawaii with Jeff Beck; Austin City Limits, 1984 (Box 14, Object 46)
      - Alabamahalle, Munich, Germany, 1984 (Box 14, Object 47)
      - Loreley, Germany; Pori Jazz Festival, Finland, 1984 August 25, 1985 (Box 14, Object 48)
      - Manor Downs, Austin, Texas; Easter Seals Telethon, Toronto, Canada, 1985 March 18, 1985 April 31 (Box 14, Object 49)
      - Seattle, Washington, 1985 September 1 (Box 14, Object 50)
      - Fox Theater, Atlanta, Georgia, 1985 November 7 (Box 14, Object 51)
      - MTV Rock Influences: The Texas Sound, Capitol Theater, Passaic, New Jersey; uncut news interview and rehearsal footage, Beaumont, Texas, 1985 (Box 14, Object 52)
      - Athens, Georgia, 1986 January 27 (Box 14, Object 53)
      - Fox Theater, Atlanta, Georgia, 1986 December 31 (Box 14, Object 54)
      - Des Moines, Iowa, 1987 August 30 (Box 14, Object 55)
      - New Orleans Jazz Festival; "Superstitious," New Orleans Heritage Festival; It's Only Rock and Roll, with Jeff Healey; In Session with Albert King, 1987 (Box 14, Object 56)
      - Blues Festival, Pistoia, Italy, 1988 July 3 (Box 14, Object 57-58)
      - Omni, Atlanta, Georgia, 1988 August 23 (Box 14, Object 59)
      - Amarillo, Texas, 1989 October 27 (Box 14, Object 60)
      - Worcester Centrum, "Going Down" with Jeff Beck; Troy, New York with Jeff Beck encore, 1989 November 8, 1989 November 12 (Box 14, Object 61)
      - Omni, Atlanta, Georgia With Jeff Beck, 1989 November 19 (Box 14, Object 62-63)
      - St. Louis, Missouri, with Joe Cocker; helicopter accident reports and videos, 1990 July 15, 1990 August 27 (Box 14, Object 64)
    - Waters, Roger with Eric Clapton: "Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking Tour"
      - Maple Leaf Garden, Toronto, Canada, 1984 July 28-1984 July 29 (Box 14, Object 65-66)
      - Montreal Forum, Quebec, Canada, 1984 July 31 (Box 14, Object 66-67)
    - Welch, Bob: Bob Welch and Friends with Stevie Nicks, Mick Fleetwood, Christine McVie, 1981 November 19 (Box 14, Object 68)
    - The Who
      - Charlton Festival, England with Pete Townshend interview, 1974 May 18 (Box 14, Object 69)
      - Cleveland, Ohio; 16 mm silent film, 1975 (Box 14, Object 70)
      - Houston Summit and extras, 1975 (Box 14, Object 71)
      - Chicago Stadium; Pontiac, Michigan; CNE Stadium, Toronto, Canada, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Object 72)
      - Grugahalle, Essen, Germany, 1981 March 28 (Box 14, Object 73)
      - Jack Murphy Stadium, San Diego, California, 1982 October 27 (Box 14, Object 74)
      - CNE Stadium, Toronto, Canada, 1989 June 23 (Box 14, Object 75)
      - Foxboro, Massachusetts news footage, 1989 July 10 (Box 14, Object 76)
      - Atlanta, Georgia, 1989 August 9 (Box 14, Object 77-78)
      - Tommy, Amphitheater, Universal City, California, 1989 August 24 (Box 14, Object 79-80)
      - Astrodome, Houston, Texas, 1989 September 2 (Box 14, Object 81-82)
      - Story of The Who, MTV Profile, 1989 (Box 14, Object 76)
    - Winter, Johnny
      - Detroit Tube Works, 1970 (Box 14, Object 83)
      - Don Kirshner's Rock Concert, 1973 (Box 12, Object 52)
      - Grugahalle, Essen, Germany, 1979 April 21 (Box 14, Object 84-85)
      - Munich, Germany; Diamond Club, Toronto, Canada, 1987 January 29, 1987 November 23 (Box 14, Object 86)
      - Pistoia Blues Festival, Italy, 1988 (Box 14, Object 87)
      - Hammerjacks, Baltimore, Maryland, 1989 August 12 (Box 14, Object 88)
      - Reno, Nevada; Madison Square Garden, New York, New York, 1990 (Box 14, Object 89)
      - Hammerjacks, Baltimore, Maryland, 1991 February 8 (Box 14, Object 90)
      - River Blues Festival, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Academy of Music, New York, New York, 1991 July 28, 1991 December 19 (Box 14, Object 91)
      - Sound FX, San Diego, California, 1991 November 10 (Box 14, Object 92-93)
      - Academy of Music, New York, New York, 1991 December 19 (Box 14, Object 93)
    - Winwood, Steve
      - Roll With It, Royal Albert Hall, London. England, 1988 (Box 14, Object 94)
      - Roll With It, MTV rockumentary; VH1 special; "Rock Block" promos; Nashville and Japan television interviews; Party at the Palace -- Queen's Jubilee Concert, 1988, 1989, 2002 (Box 14, Object 95)
      - Shoreline Amphitheater, Mountainview, California, 1989 (Box 14, Object 96)
      - Kanagawa Arena, Yokohama, Japan, 1991 March 22 (Box 14, Object 97)
      - Sound Stage, 2004-2005 (Box 14, Object 98-99)
      - Highclere Castle, Berkshire, England with Eric Clapton, 2007 May 18-2007 May 19 (Box 14, Object 100-102)
      - Promo videos, undated (Box 13, Object 106)
    - Young, Neil
      - "Blue Notes Tour": Toronto, Canada; Darien Lake, New York, 1988 August 18-1988 August 19 (Box 14, Object 103)
      - Tokyo, Japan, 1989 April 28 (Box 14, Object 104)
      - Madison Square Garden, New York, New York, 1991 February 4 (Box 14, Object 105)
      - Nassau Coliseum, New York, New York, 1991 February 22 (Box 14, Object 106)
      - Beacon Theater, New York, New York, 1992 February 13, 1992 February 15 (Box 14, Object 107-108)
    - Zucchero: Zucchero and Guests including Eric Clapton, Royal Albert Hall, London, England, 2004 May 6 (Box 14, Object 109-110)
    - ZZ Top
      - Grugahalle, Essen, Germany; Stockholm, Sweden; Best of Rock-Pop In Concert, "Groovy Little Hippie Pad", 1980 April 19, 1983 and undated (Box 14, Object 111)
      - Westfalenhalle, Dortmund, Germany; Tonight Show; Sharp Dressed Men, 1982-1986 (Box 14, Object 112)
      - Japanese television, live and interviews, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Object 113)
      - Maple Leaf Gardens, Toronto, Canada, 1990 October 11 (Box 14, Object 114)
      - Civic Center, Hartford, Connecticut, 1991 January 18 (Box 14, Object 115)
      - Nassau Coliseum, Uniondale, New York; International Rock Music Awards; Willie Nelson's 70th Birthday Bash, 1991, 2003 (Box 14, Object 116)
      - Madison Square Garden, New York, New York, 1994 June 6 (Box 14, Object 117)
  - Subseries 3: Audiocassettes [RESTRICTED], circa 1960s-2000s (Box 81-84, Box 33-44, Box 17-32, Box 57-68, Box 45-56, Box 15-16, Box 69-80)
    The items in Subseries 2: Audiocassettes are in their original order as received from the donor and consist of 1,305 audiocassettes. Content for Eric Clapton, Alvin Lee, and Ten Years After comprise the bulk of the Subseries, while a significant number of audiocassettes are also devoted to Jimi Hendrix, Led Zeppelin, and The Rolling Stones. Other performers represented in the Subseries include Aerosmith, Jan Ackerman, Allman Brothers, Animals, Atlanta Rhythm Section, Bad Company, Badfinger, Band, Ginger Baker, Beatles, Beck, Bogart, and Appice, Jeff Beck, Pat Benatar, Chuck Berry, Big Brother and the Holding Company, Elvin Bishop, Blind Faith, Jack Bruce, Roy Buchanan, Paul Butterfield, Byrds, J.J. Cale, Canned Heat, Joe Cocker, Phil Collins, Robert Cray, Cream, Creedence Clearwater Revival, Crosby, Stills, Nash, and Young, Deep Purple, Delaney and Bonnie, Derek and the Dominos, Dire Straits, Doors, Bob Dylan, Eagles, Faces, Firm, Fleetwood Mac, John Fogerty, Foghat, Foreigner, Peter Frampton, Free, Rory Gallagher, Grand Funk Railroad, Peter Green, Buddy Guy, George Harrison, Jeff Healey, Heart, Hot Tuna, Humble Pie, Jefferson Airplane, Jethro Tull, Katrina and the Waves, Greg Kihn, Albert King, B.B. King, Freddie King, Kinks, Leo Kottke, Little Feat, Lynyrd Skynyrd, Mamas and the Papas, Mahavishnu Orchestra, Steve Marriott, Dave Mason, John Mayall, John McLaughlin, Melanie, Moody Blues, Gary Moore, Jim Morrison, Muddy Waters, Note For Note, Robert Palmer, Jimmy Page and Robert Plant, Pink Floyd, Procol Harum, Linda Rondstadt, Santana, Savoy Brown, Steely Dan, Steppenwolf, Cat Stevens, Stephen Stills, Mick Taylor, Ten Years Later, Thin Lizzy, Robin Tower, Traffic, Stevie Ray Vaughan, Gene Vincent, Junior Wells, Roger Waters, Who, Edgar Winter, Johnny Winter, Steve Winwood, Wishbone Ash, Yardbirds, and Neil Young.
    The condition of these materials has not yet been determined for playback purposes. Access copies of these materials may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  - Subseries 4: VHS Videocassettes [RESTRICTED], circa 1960s-2000s (Box 118-119, Box 87-90, Box 91-94, Box 85-86, Box 103-106, Box 107-110, Box 95-98, Box 99-102, Box 111-112)
    Items in Subseries 5: VHS Videocassettes are in their original order as received from the donor and consist of 960 VHS videocassettes. Content on Eric Clapton, Alvin Lee, and Ten Years After comprise the bulk of the Subseries, which also includes footage from television programs and festivals. Other performers represented in the Subseries include AC/DC, Aerosmith, Allman Brothers, Animals, Bad Company, Randy Bachman, Ginger Baker, Band, Bangles, Beatles, Jeff Beck, Bee Gees, Pat Benatar, Blondie, Byrds, Jack Bruce, Eric Burden, Joe Cocker, Cream, Creedence Clearwater Revival, Jim Croce, Crosby, Stills, Nash, and Young, Burton Cummings, Deep Purple, Doors, Bob Dylan, Eagles, Faces, Fleetwood Mac, John Fogerty, Foghat, Peter Frampton, Rory Gallagher, Guess Who, Buddy Guy, George Harrison, Richie Havens, Jeff Healey, Heart, Jimi Hendrix, J. Geils Band, Jefferson Airplane, Joan Jett, Jethro Tull, Elton John, Janis Joplin, B.B. King, Freddie King, Kinks, Al Kooper, Led Zeppelin, John Lennon, Little Feat, Lone Justice, Los Lobos, Lynyrd Skynayrd, Dave Mason, John Mayall, Paul McCartney, Roger McGuinn, Joni Mitchell, Moody Blues, Gary Moore, Van Morrison, Moutain, Muddy Waters, Stevie Nicks, Notting Hillibillies, Jimmy Page, Tom Petty, Pink Floyd, Plastic Ono Band, Police, Pretenders, Rainbow, Bonnie Raitt, Rolling Stones, Linda Rondstadt, Santana, Savoy Brown, Dusty Springfield, Ringo Starr, Mick Taylor, Robin Trower, Stevie Ray Vaughan, Pete Townshend, Tina Turner, Joe Walsh, Roger Waters, Who, Johnny Winter, Steve Winwood, Yardbirds, Yes, Neil Young, Frank Zappa, Zucchero, and ZZ Top. Television programs and festivals featured in the Subseries include American Bandstand, Beat Club, Beat! Beat! Beat!, California Jam, California Screamin’, Colour Me Pop, Dick Cavett Show, Don Kirshner’s Rock Concert, Ed Sullivan Show, How It Is, Isle of Wight Pop Festival, Johnny Cash Show, Live From the Bitter End, Midnight Special, Old Grey Whistle Test, Ready, Steady, Go!, Shindig, Smothers Brothers Comedy Hour, Top of the Pops, Woodstock, and Woodstock ‘94.
  - Subseries 5: Beta Videocassettes [RESTRICTED], circa 1960s-2000s (Box 113-114, Box 115-117)
    The audiovisual material in this subseries is on a defunct media format and, therefore, is RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  - Subseries 6: Film Reels [RESTRICTED], 1973
    The audiovisual material in this subseries is on a defunct media format and, therefore, is RESTRICTED. An access copy of this material will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to this material is available.
    - Ten Years After, Japan, 1973 (Box 84)
  - Subseries 7: MiniDiscs [RESTRICTED], circa 2000
    The audiovisual material in this series is on a defunct media format and, therefore, is RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    Subseries 7: MiniDiscs consists of two MiniDiscs, one sent to Herb Staehr by Luky Schrempf.
    - Lee, Alvin: Copenhagen, 2000 July 9 (Box 84)
    - Clapton, Eric: Royal Albert Hall, 1987 January 11 (Box 84)
- Series VII: Contact Sheets, 1968-1977, 2002, undated (Box 120, Folder 4)
  Series VII: Contact Sheets spans the years 1968 to 1977 and 2002, and includes some undated material. The Series consists of one folder of contact sheets, correspondence, and notes from the photographers' whose work is featured, and a magazine article related to the New Yardbirds' (Led Zeppelin) first concert. The contact sheets contain photographs of Blind Faith, Eric Clapton, Jimi Hendrix, Jeff Beck Group, Led Zeppelin, The New Yardbirds, Ten Years After, Johnny Winter, and The Yardbirds. Credited photographers: Jørgen Angel, DAGMAR, and Steen Møller Rasmussen.